From this tiny Malaysian fishing village,
these 16 Americans are beginning the
adventure of a lifetime.
And
right here, a beautiful but dangerous
jungle in the middle of
Elves.
No creature comforts.
They are wiping the slate clean.
Turn
to adapt or they are voted off.
In
these 16 people, one survivor.
The 16 contestants have been separated
into two tribes named after the beaches
where they will live.
Sean Kenna, a neurologist from Long
Island.
Kelly Wigglesworth, a river guide from Las
Vegas.
Rudy Bosch, a retiree
three-year-old cancer survivor from San
Francisco.
Richard Hatch, a corporate communications
consultant from Rhode Island.
Susan Hock, a truck driver from Wisconsin.
Dirk Bean, a young dairy farmer, also from
Wisconsin.
And Stacy Stillman, a litigation attorney
from San Francisco.
Jervis Peterson, a YMCA basketball coach
from Philadelphia.
Colleen Haskell, an advertising student
from Miami.
B.B.
Anderson, a real estate developer from
Kansas City.
Ramona Gray, a biochemist from New Jersey.
Gretchen Cordy, a preschool teacher from
Tennessee.
Greg Buis, a recent Ivy League graduate
from Colorado.
Jenna Lewis, a single mother and full-time
student from New Hampshire.
And Joel Kluge, a health club consultant
from Little Rock.
A few years
ago, this group met for the first time in
a small fishing village on the coast of
Borneo.
Their minds racing with questions,
wondering, can I do this?
This is more than just a test of survival
skills.
It's also a test of social skills.
Here, it's the impressions you make on the
other castaways that determines your fate.
Under the rules, one tribe must visit
tribal council every three days with a
single purpose.
Vote one of their own members off the
island.
To win, you must survive the island,
survive the boat, and ultimately, survive
each other.
Paddling over, we had two or three of
those boxes in the water, dragging them
behind the raft.
And that is dumb.
I said, let's get them boxes aboard.
It'll be a lot easier.
You know, that's dead weight you got.
He was yelling at everybody.
Let's lose the box.
Cut it loose now.
He may be 72 years old and an ex-Navy
SEAL, but that doesn't mean that this is
his world.
Rudy, Sean, Stacy, can we take like 15
minutes and just talk before we do
anything?
Can we piss first?
Just a suggestion.
Should we take a break?
No, keep battling.
One break in a time, one water break in a
time.
I don't like being on the water all that
much.
So, I mean, the whole motion like this.
And we're rowing.
We have like 100 pounds of stuff on the
raft.
I just, I started heaving.
Good job.
Way not to put on it.
I'm used to being in a lab with my lab put
on, in the air conditioning.
But this is like outdoors, 24-7.
And you're exerting energy like almost all
of that time.
This is just day one.
Should
we start moving the left up?
Hey, let's discuss some things, man.
Let's figure some things out.
Here's what we plan on doing.
High tide is that line right there.
See that line?
Uh-huh.
So it shouldn't come up to here.
Right.
And this piece of bamboo back here, we can
lay it from up here over to there.
Oh, that guy's a similar clearing, but
none of us.
Actually, it's before we build the
shelter, just knock that whole...
Yeah, yeah.
No, I mean, this is enough crap on us to
say that.
What's the first thing we need to do?
Okay.
Shelter.
We need a latrine.
Okay, so we don't need fire tonight?
Is that what we're saying?
No.
That's an option.
We got enough water to make it tonight,
you think?
You guys, I think the first thing we ought
to do is talk about how we're going to do
whatever we're going to do.
That's what we're doing.
Talk about the process.
All right.
Listen, listen.
Let me give you a quick.
The cap will be right there.
We'll clear these leaves up.
That's a flat piece of ground.
The latrine will be down there.
The wind's hitting me in the back right
now.
So we're saying we need a latrine, and we
just need a clear place to sleep.
Is that all we want tonight?
Off the ground.
Let's check the bus.
Let's see what we've got.
What do I say?
There might be a blowtorch in there.
We need a bathroom.
Are you guys all done talking?
Yeah, we're going to ask.
Huh?
I'm done, though.
I'm going to open up a box.
I'm looking for freedom, man.
Rich, I appreciate what he's trying to do
as far as bring the team together and
stuff, because that's one thing that needs
to happen.
I think he's got some good skills in that
area, and unfortunately, people like that
annoy me.
I'm just thinking.
I think we're off to a bad start.
Why?
Because we're not talking?
Sometimes, though, Richard, you kind of
got to do things and talk as you go along,
and sometimes things can't be that planned
out.
I agree with you.
The problem with having no conversation
whatsoever or lots of people talking about
different things is that nobody's working
toward a particular goal.
Not the silly little stuff about, oh,
who's going to sleep?
What are we going to do?
But why are we here?
And what's the point?
And if we don't...
Oh, I figured that out before I come here.
For you.
But you haven't?
And I have for me.
But we haven't for us.
And for the next seven ejections, 21 days,
we have to function together or we fail.
What do you think we're doing now?
Not functioning together at all.
I'm a redneck.
And I don't know corporate world at all.
And corporate world ain't going to work
out here in the bush.
No, and I'm not talking corporate world.
I'm talking creating a team.
And working together.
We're doing good.
But, see, so the creating team is actually
putting all of our hands together and
walking and...
Not hands.
All of us knowing what we're doing.
The head thing, yeah.
But that's...
Action, man.
Action, Richard.
Yeah.
Action.
You don't want to act ahead.
I'm good to go, survival-wise.
People-wise, it'll be a little more
challenging.
But I've got the million-dollar check
written already.
I mean, I'm the winner.
And it's that kind of cocky attitude that
makes people really hate your gut.
So that's the kind of thing I've really
got to keep under wraps.
But it's just, how do I get there from
here?
Oh,
look at this, folks!
Woo!
What is it?
If this is carotene, and we're going to
take one of those lamps...
Oh, we can make torches and stuff out of
twine.
We can twine all the time.
What is that?
We match it.
Yeah, look.
It's definitely biscuits, because we've
got corn.
Oh, look.
We've got a frying pan.
Oh, we are so set.
Look, I'm shaking it.
Can anyone hear the biscuits?
Oh-ho!
We've got a clean flat!
Woo!
That's all the train.
I said we dig a hole, put this here, knock
the port out of the bottom.
Then we can just keep moving in.
We've got a nice hole.
We should just sit down and have a talk
about what the hell we're going to do.
Can I help?
When I asked earlier about having a
conversation, that's what I was talking
about.
And I really can help with how we can do
that.
You guys, we came over here to talk.
What happens when people get together is,
if they aren't all headed in the same
direction toward a particular goal, then
things that individuals do kind of get in
the way of the whole team.
And I think it's really, really important
that what we decide be decided as a group.
So if you hear somebody saying something
and you're all aggravated with them, stop.
Don't try to make your point and try and
help them make theirs.
So for example, you know Sean, what do you
think the main point of what I'm trying to
say now is?
I've been daydreaming, thinking, what am I
going to eat?
That's a real big way to figure it out.
As long as they can hit the middle of this
hole, we don't freeze.
A long...
Start here.
We start here.
We go back to the other stream down there.
Here's where we are right here.
We have to go across the stream.
We go across one stream, two streams,
three streams.
Alright.
You know that?
Okay, is this the path?
Well, it said newly cut path.
It was newly cut.
Trail washes out.
Oh, the trail washes out.
Oh, what?
No?
Why don't you stay there for a minute.
Let me walk to keep you in sight.
Okay.
To see if I see anything that resembles
anything.
You see anything?
Look at here.
Well, I mean, come here and look at it.
Okay, ready?
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
Yeah.
There we are.
Go ahead.
Alright.
Way to go, baby.
Don't let me drop sweat in that.
Okay, we're almost full.
You know, we could never do this, but you
know what?
The thought crossed my mind.
What?
As long as you and I always know where the
water is...
We've got control of the water map.
No one else will be able to vote you or I
out.
We're not giving up the secrets of the
water supply.
That's right.
This thing is Viagra.
Viagra.
That's his nickname.
You got to...
You know, you got to do what you got to
do, right?
If we don't keep some humor, we'll go mad.
Good
job.
The hardest part is hanging around with
all these young kids.
I don't even know what MTV means, you
know?
And I'm used to being in the military and
one guy stands up, he gives an order and
there's no back talk.
You know, like yesterday, everybody's
trying to run the show.
And if they'd let one person do it, we'd
be much better off.
But trying to keep them all shut up is
hard.
If they listened to me, they'd all have
haircuts and everything else, you know?
We'd be in formation in the morning and
all that kind of stuff.
But they're not going to do that.
I got to fit in, not them.
You know, there's more of them than there
is of me.
Hey, you got a pierced nipple, eh?
Yeah, I got the old pierced nipple thing.
How does that feel?
Pretty edgy for a doctor, right?
Yeah, yeah.
I thought I was making it with the hair.
And then this morning, man, when I ran my
hands through it, I fell from a couple of,
like, softball-sized knots in it.
I'm like, nah, they're going to come out
now.
I was doing something.
I don't even remember how I did it.
Bated on won't hurt it.
Yeah, so we'll give it a little shot of
bated on, too.
Please.
I think these are the only sponges we
have, so I'm just going to keep reusing a
little bit.
Yeah.
Okay.
I've been thrashing around like I'm 35,
instead of acting my age.
But we have a doctor in our tribe, Sean,
and he did a wonderful job of bandaging me
up.
I think one of the problems with aging is
the thinning of the skin, darn it.
And so I think I'm maybe getting a little
more banged up than some of the younger
ones.
I'm able to do something bizarre, but
we're getting there.
Try this.
I don't know.
Heavier.
That's a little sharper though.
He's awesome.
Oh.
That ain't going to work.
Here's the therapist version of Bye Bye
Blues.
If I can remember it, I will.
Bye, bye, blues.
Thanks to Prozac.
Give me Paxil.
They'll bring birds sing.
Sun is shining.
No more whining.
My limb through.
Da-da-da-da-da.
Light is as hell, but I'm swell.
Bye, bye, bye, blues.
Yeah, it's awesome.
Awesome.
Fantastic.
Well, the fish traps were hanging from the
boat that we were coming over here.
And when we were tossed into the sea on
the raft and we could take whatever we
could get our hands on, we grabbed three
or four fish traps and a bunch of rat
traps.
And so we stuck the rat traps out the
first night, and boom, we got a rat in
each of them.
I didn't sleep at all.
I mean, we closed our eyes.
We kept hearing noises and, like, cooking
sounds.
And we were like, okay, what's his name?
Joel woke up, a rat was, like, in his ear.
I heard something squeaking in my ear
every time a rat was trying to get on the
raft.
Or get near us or get at something.
I mean, everything was moving.
Well, we're just going along with the
beach here and just identifying whatever
we can use for the shelter, the roof.
And we're a little irritated that none of
the others don't want to help carry stuff,
but that's okay.
We need five more of these.
Bebe.
He's a character, man.
I don't think he likes me much.
Just these.
No, you don't understand.
I've got to have this thought out and
positioned right.
Okay.
Just, just, Joel, trust me.
I'm not, I'm not the one bitching.
No, I know.
I mean, I'm, I'm fine.
He's talking to me about monkey business.
I can't sleep, so I'm usually up on the
job.
Just being the whip.
We got a lot of lazy people, if you don't
know the truth.
You can't do it all yourself.
You know, I asked Colleen to straighten
this out for me.
And here it is.
It's the only thing she had to do today.
She can't have lazy people.
He had been out there, you know, all
morning long.
And, um, you know, it was hot.
Baby, I thought we said this was the time
of day we were going to see out of the
sun.
Well, but for some of the people, it's
been all day that way.
All right, it's your turn.
You tell me what you're doing here, and
I'll help you.
You hold it up, and I'll do it quick.
I promise you, I'll do it quick.
That, you know, that's the right way to do
it quick.
We won't have near enough line to build
the roof and do that if we do all this.
It's an off hammer.
Anyway, don't stop now, but...
I think there's plenty.
And I'm gonna roll that up for you, too.
We can't, like, get burned out, though.
I'm not burned out.
I know, but you will be if you spend all
day out in the sun.
No, no.
I never get burned out.
You don't know me.
I don't know you, but I know human beings.
Okay.
I like working as a hobby.
Honest to God, how about 15 minutes,
though?
What?
Get down for 15 minutes.
Yeah, but I want to get...
I want to get this thing stabilized.
But, Phoebe, look...
So at least...
See, let me just explain.
I want to get this stabilized, so then
people can come in.
You know, with that light cord you got?
And we can tie these things down.
But until I get this bounce out of this, I
want to put a support there, in the middle
here, and right there.
Because if not, we got to take bounce out
of this.
I just think we have plenty of time.
I thought we were going to try to stay
competitive.
And if you work all day and you're burnt
at the end of the day, we're not going to
be competitive.
Take a break, and if it bounces a little
tonight, then we'll fix it tomorrow.
I'm going to keep working.
We are.
You're going to...
Are you going to work?
No, I'm not.
Yeah, you are.
Oh, my.
You're doing fine.
Too much paper?
Yeah.
You're a man, B.
No.
I just...
We're both a man.
And made it happen.
The fire started because I had bought a
set of glasses with me.
I was going to do it, and Gretchen said,
why don't I do it?
I know how to do it, too.
So I said, great.
Nice, guys.
Nice split up and everything.
Amen.
Good work.
And she took my glasses and started the
fire.
You did well, Gretchen.
If we get fire, it means we're going to
have a hot meal in our stomach, which is
going to bring up tea morale.
That first hot meal might be rat soup,
which I'm, like, looking forward to very
much because there's nothing wrong with
the rat.
All a rat is is a squirrel without a fuzzy
tail.
Let's just work with this.
Okay.
I'm thinking that's just...
If we could just work with this, I mean,
we're getting a ton of smoke.
Now we just got to figure out...
Oh, and start that piece of wood?
So if we get a piece of bamboo, someone
sits here and pulls the bamboo right here
with the kindling in it.
With the kindling in it.
You know what I'm saying?
There you go.
Come on, Dirk.
Take
a break, man.
We made a lot of smoke, but no fire.
I think that it would have been nice if we
had fire.
We're not going to catch fish unless we
have fire to cook it.
And I think that if we had fire, we could
have spent a lot of time sitting around
the bonfire at night and maybe sing us
songs.
We have a ukulele, you know?
And that didn't happen, and I wish it did.
Throughout their time on the island, the
tribes will compete in a series of
challenges.
They'll receive messages notifying them of
these competitions at their tree mail.
Today's challenge is for both reward in
the form of 50 waterproof matches and
immunity.
When immunity, you stay on the island a
few days longer.
Lose, face tribal council, where you must
vote one member off the island.
Pam, just a reminder of your first night.
It looks so easy in the book.
Yes.
Why is it so hard to light?
Tonight, your tribe will carry the torch.
One tribe takes home the flame.
The other gives someone the boost.
Whoa!
Whoa, immunity challenge with time.
That's the competition is taking home the
flame.
But what's the competition?
We've got no freaking idea.
Welcome tribes to your first challenge.
Congratulations on your first night on the
island.
You should be very proud.
I know both of you guys have food.
You found some fresh water.
And I think, Pagong, you guys had fire.
Woo!
Yeah!
A lot of work to get fire, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, it takes a lot of work.
A lot.
With the threat of rain, always a
constant.
Even if you guys did have fire, you're
certainly not back there tending to them
now.
50 waterproof matches should certainly
make that a lot easier.
It's one of the things you're playing for
tonight.
The other is this.
I want everybody to touch this.
Get a good feel of this.
This is your life on the island.
This is the immunity idol.
Win this, you stay on the island a few
days longer.
Lose, you face tomorrow's tribal council
where one of you will be the first person
boated off the island.
Big enough stakes?
Oh yeah!
Okay, here's what we're doing.
There are two rafts about 150 feet out in
the water.
Your job is to get your raft back to the
beach.
Along the way, a series of torches both in
the water and on the land.
First team to light all their torches and
their side of the fire spirit wins
immunity.
Here are the rules.
Each tribe member has to have one hand on
the raft at all times.
At all times.
Nobody can swim ahead.
Nobody can fall behind.
The other rule?
You have to light every torch.
Don't put me in the position of having to
make a judgement call.
I don't want to.
There's too much at stake.
Clear?
Clear.
Alright.
Swim out to your rafts.
Wait for my signal.
Great competition.
Really close.
Begong.
You get fire in the form of 50 water for a
matchup.
Nice competition.
You know the drill.
You have a date with me tomorrow for the
tribal council.
Where one of you will be the first person
voted off.
Oh, he does?
He brought his bible?
Yeah, yeah.
I think he's pretty religious.
He was telling me he was a Jewish
minister.
Wash.
Before we got on the island here, I formed
opinions about people.
But I changed my mind just on that trip
in.
He's rich, for one.
I mean, this guy, he's strong.
He's smart.
This guy surprises me.
You know, he's fat, but he's good.
You can just lay it right over those.
I like Rudy.
I'm not bothered by his
straightforwardness at all.
I don't think it's even a problem.
I like it that he's saying, hey, do this,
or hey, do that.
But people are thinking of that as very
direct and arrogant.
That's the word I'm hearing.
And I'm thinking to myself, well, they
think he's arrogant.
Oh, my God.
I'm out of here.
What do we got?
The good news is we'll be having fire
tonight.
The bad news is one of us won't be here to
enjoy it.
We've got the tribal council tonight.
Pack your bags.
Get ready to go.
Which one it will be, the world will soon
know.
Unfortunately, we're going to have to vote
somebody off.
There's going to be a lot of tension.
And one of us is going to leave.
What time are we going to do this at?
We just said get ready to go.
Pack your bags.
Get ready to go.
I can't believe we have to pack up.
We're just getting settled.
Well, somebody's bored.
Somebody's gone.
So it's time to think about who are they
going to vote for?
Why are they going to vote?
I've narrowed it down to four.
I'm one of them.
Well, it could mean a lot.
Either staying or being voted out.
You know, last night's competition, I
really feel responsible.
Because I couldn't keep up.
And I was dragged totally off my feet.
I do feel that that stumble probably cost
us the immunity challenge.
And that's a big one.
Up until probably last night, I never gave
it a second thought about who I was going
to vote off.
Or if I got voted off.
But after last night, I thought about it
then.
And I decided then.
I feel pretty secure, actually, about the
vote tonight.
Kelly and I get along real well.
And we've been talking about strategy.
And, you know, who's not contributing as
much.
And who would be best to vote off.
And I think we've come to a mutual
decision.
And we've talked to Sue about it.
Stacy came up to me.
It's like, she don't like Rudy.
And she's like, oh, we think we're going
to vote for Rudy.
And we'll vote him off because she's so
barking.
Why anybody's too barking too bossy is
Stacy.
Because she doesn't move her ass.
The chicks think I'm voting for one person
and I'm not.
This is tribal council.
Where each week, one member will be voted
off the island.
Last night, in a crushing defeat, Tagi
lost the immunity challenge.
So tonight, they will come here and vote
the first person off.
It all begins with a dangerous hike
through the jungle.
With so little time to get acquainted,
everyone is vulnerable.
Rich's talk versus action approach may be
more annoying than helpful.
Sonia's tumble cost them dearly.
One thing's for certain, at tribal
council, you are held accountable for your
actions.
There will be a vote.
Someone is going home.
I see torches.
Oh, that looks pretty hairy.
Make your way around.
We begin tribal council with a ritual.
Behind each view is a torch.
I'd like you to grab the torch and
approach the fire.
Go ahead and dip your torches in the
flame.
Light them.
Put them back in their slot and take a
seat.
We do this because, as I'm sure you've
discovered, on the island, fire represents
life.
These torches now represent your life,
your identity here at tribal council.
The good news is you will take these
torches with you when you leave.
So you will have fire and you will bring
them back with you to each tribal council.
Go ahead and have a seat.
Well, leave it to me to state the obvious,
but this is not a place you want to be.
You tread in dangerous territory every
time you come here.
Tribal council is basically where you
account for your actions on the island.
Some of those actions will come back to
help you.
Some of them may come back to haunt you.
But tonight, based on those actions, one
of you will be the first person voted off
the island.
So, before we get to the vote, let's talk
about what's been going on.
I'm curious just about you guys getting
here and finding this place.
How was the journey over here?
Two deadly snakes.
Really?
Grand Canyon, mud flies.
It was great.
Fun.
We're still starving.
We still haven't eaten.
We've eaten, but not really eaten.
The competition is stiffer.
The competition we had last night was
tougher than I had anticipated.
How are you holding up physically?
Well, pretty well.
You know, I'll fight to the finish.
I have my blisters and footnotes, but I'm
doing okay.
What happened after Quest for Fire?
That was a great competition.
Obviously a lot at stake.
We came close.
We almost got them.
We came back.
We were right there.
We almost got them.
There's no way.
Alright guys, well, it's obviously a fun
group.
This is not a pleasant process.
And I know also from listening to you guys
talk that there are a lot of different
reasons why you're here.
Obviously a million dollars, big motivator
for anybody.
But I'm sensing there could be personal
reasons, different journeys you might be
on that this encompasses.
Whatever it is, to fulfill that agenda,
you have to survive tonight's Tribal
Council.
That's the way it's set up.
So, what we're going to do is vote.
And how it will work is, we'll come down
here.
We'll go across this bridge into our
voting confessional.
Write the name of the person you want to
vote off.
Large, clear letters.
Hold it up and speak your peace.
We can't hear you.
Fold it up.
Put it in the container.
Come back and take a seat.
Now, once the votes are tallied, the
decision is final.
And you have to leave the Tribal Council
area immediately.
It's time to vote.
You're first.
The
weakest link in the crew.
Tough call.
He's an ornery guy.
Doesn't really help that much.
For a Navy SEAL, he doesn't know how to
start fire.
And he just criticizes everything.
She's the reason we lost yesterday.
I
miss his skills and speaking his mind
openly.
...on the courage it's taken to get this
far.
There were a lot of steps along the way
any of you could have turned around.
Nobody did.
And in my book, that gives you bragging
rights for life.
So with that, I'll read the votes.
First vote.
Sonya.
Rudy.
That's three for Sonya and three for Rudy.
First person voted off the island.
I
need you to grab your torch and bring it
to me.
The tribe has spoken.
Well, to the rest of you, I guess, a
somber congratulations.
You've survived the tribal council.
You have fire.
You can head back to camp and I will see
you tomorrow for the next challenge.
Good night.
Next week on Survivor.
I've been working my ass off and a lot of
you have been laying on your ass watching
me.
Don't give me any of that.
Me and Richard got to be pretty good
friends.
Not in a homosexual way, that's for sure.
Well, I think this has been an awesome
experience.
Being the first to be voted out is a
little humiliating.
On the other hand, the team did the right
thing.
They're a terrific group of people.
They're very strong physically.
And I think in their shoes, I'd probably
do the same thing.
...
To be continued...