Sixteen Americans forced to abandon ship
in the middle of the South China Sea.
Marooned for 39 days.
They must work together to build shelter,
find food, and survive the island.
But ultimately, it is everyone for
themselves.
Every third night, they will hike deep
into the jungle to take part in
the...
In the end, only one...
Tensions at Tagi Tribe were on the rise.
You guys wait for three days fishing.
It's expected to get on each other's
nerves.
While at Pagong, the mood was downcast.
I think the camp looks trashy.
Something's gonna have to happen to make
everybody decide to pitch in.
But at the reward challenge, Pagong
rebounded by winning a special food prize.
Chicken!
Are you kidding me?
The romance began to bloom.
Colleen has joined me in the forest to
sleep.
I noticed they seem to be spending their
nights out into the stars.
I think it's a little romance going on.
It's all about sex.
Back at Tagi, Dirk was running on empty.
You're looking like hell.
I definitely lost a lot of muscle mass, a
lot of strength.
And his tribe thought they had the
immunity challenge wrapped up.
Apparently, we need one rower and the rest
of us are swimming.
I'm a commercial whitewater raft guide.
I know Jervis can't swim.
My guess is that they're gonna put him in
the boat rowing.
I could beat him any day of the week.
But their overconfidence cost them dearly.
That was the winning job!
I got beat by a guy who can't even swim.
Their loss sent them back to tribal
council, where the voting alliance reared
its ugly head.
Dirk, Travis spoke.
11 castaways remain.
Who will be voted off tonight?
Stay 16 on the island.
The survivors are starting to plan for
their future.
Until
they build separate societies and have
established their own routines.
But in the game of survivor, everything
must change.
Three days from now, the two tribes will
be forced to merge into a single new
tribe.
Will they continue to vote along old
tribal lines after the merger?
Or will it be everyone for themselves?
This week's episode finds the impending
merger on everyone's mind.
Time.
Change is coming.
People, I don't think they're taking this
seriously.
They think that they're gonna go to their
little mud volcano and give each other
facials.
It's not a T-minus-1 heart.
Not everybody wants to participate in the
chopping of the head.
I can't.
I mean, come on.
It's not too good.
There's not gonna be a trace of that thing
on earth.
I don't have any emotional attachment.
From the moment I saw them, they were
food.
They, you know, they never were pets to
me.
I don't enjoy killing things.
It's not like a thrill to kill something.
But anybody who eats meat has to realize
that somebody killed that.
Someone's killing it for you.
I don't want to watch it die.
I want to have it put on my plate and put
it in front of me.
I'm missing food the most.
I mean, I could go for some chicken right
now.
Anytime.
Bait.
I don't care.
Food.
Go ahead.
One, two, three.
I just like to ignore that whole act of
preaching.
The whole death part.
Oh, we're gonna eat three chickens in
three days.
Because we want to eat them before we
merge tribes.
We don't want them getting any of our
chickens.
Besides, one of them was pecking the hell
out of me.
It is the one that was pecking me.
Interacted with the chickens as little as
possible.
I'm not petting them, putting them on
leashes, taking them for walks, naming
them and, you know, calling them my very
own.
It does no good to befriend dinner.
I've never gone through the process of
feeding a chicken, watering a chicken,
then butchering a chicken.
Yum.
It's
greasy.
And it's gonna fry and it's gonna bubble
and...
Mmm, dinner.
Chicken!
Yeah, we're lucky now.
Got my greasy flavor back in my mouth.
People were happy before I know that the
nutrition hit their bodies.
It was, I think, the first really
recognizable piece of protein that people
have had, that, you know, everybody kind
of knew what it was and make you feel like
you chewed on something.
I think, mentally, the chicken was more
important than it was physically.
I mean, we have three chickens.
And we're done eating those.
It's
funny when I hear, how come you're naked
all the time?
I'm naked less than 1% of the time.
I'd like to be naked all the time.
That would be smarter in this 100-degree
weather.
They're
on naked quite a bit.
I think it probably bugs some of the guys.
Seems kind of childish and immature to me
and kind of grandstanding and walking
around on national TV.
Your life, my life, different things.
Who cares?
Something like that.
He runs around pretty often with clothes
on and he don't thinks nothing of it.
Peachy.
I couldn't care less whether guys or girls
are around.
It doesn't make any difference.
Is there any horny gay man out there that
want a horny guy in the car?
And I know one.
Naked isn't sexual to me.
And it doesn't...
I don't think of it that way.
It doesn't faze me that way.
So no, I'm pretty comfortable naked.
I don't agree with his lifestyle and I
told him that.
And he probably don't agree with mine.
But anyway, we gotta work together.
Up until this merger anyway.
There's money at stake.
We're all trying to win the pot.
I finally went along with this alliance.
And if I didn't, I'd be out of here
probably the next vote or the one after.
I think with an alliance that we establish
here, we can do very, very well.
If you don't, you're out.
Exactly.
Tell me what option you have, Rudy.
I've been trying to support keeping Rudy
from day one.
I want to bring him along to the next
round where he won't care much and
probably will get voted off before
winning.
You think they wouldn't do it to us?
No, of course they wouldn't.
I don't think somebody's in control of our
group in particular.
I think I'm in control of who's being
voted off.
And I think that's all that matters to me.
Totally dumb statement now that I regret.
You know, it was kind of just to poke at
the girls, give them a little shot.
He sets it up first with, don't take
offense to this, but women are the
stupidest things on the planet next to
cows.
Girls are the stupidest thing on the
planet next to cows, was the remark.
The
story was, we were talking about
relationships and how guys and girls will
do stupid things if you like the person.
We never got around to the stupid things
guys do.
If you like somebody that much, you'll do
something stupid for them that you should
maybe not do.
We're not as stupid as ours, we're a step
above.
Well, I said, you know, Jervis, I told
those girls that all they had to do was
like, when they write your name on that
piece of paper and hold it up to the
camera, they can look straight into the
lens and go, nooo, he had his mouth
dropped open like he had never considered
that maybe that was not the best thing to
say to a woman who had that much power
over him.
No, I'm being very apologetic because it
was stupid.
I mean, after I said it, you know, after I
said it...
He was like in this box with no freaking
way out.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
If you let them talk long enough, they'll
probably get you out of the box.
They're good for that.
Jervis, he's on a free ride, man.
He's untouchable.
I don't know how he gets through.
He's called the women cows.
He doesn't do stuff half the time.
I haven't done a thing out here since I've
been here, it seems like.
And that's cool.
Joel does the fishing.
He does the paddling.
I'm just out there hanging on the raft
with him.
The expert fisherman that I am.
When they built that hut on the beach, I
was nowhere near there.
I was in the shade somewhere.
You know, I was looking for a coconut or
something.
I think everybody has done cooking rice at
one point in time.
I have yet to cook anything.
I didn't see him do anything yesterday.
But that is nothing new and that surprises
me that I still haven't voted for Jervis.
He doesn't seem to pull his own weight and
I know for a fact that he voted against
me.
So why the hell have I voted for him?
I don't know.
I knew coming here was all about charm and
personality.
That would get me through.
The Tagi tribe has lost the last two
reward challenges and they're growing more
hungry each day.
But tonight there is another reward
challenge for food.
Smell anything yet?
Larvae and tomato sauce.
Nice.
I know.
We don't know if it's even his food.
Maybe it's water.
Ruin that chicken with damn dog food.
Go for it.
Exactly.
Coat, nice and shiny.
Yeah, your hair will look good.
Here, take a taste.
Be a man.
Put your finger in there and eat it.
Are you gonna eat it with me?
I
choose my preservatives and chemicals
wisely and that really would have thrown
everything off balance.
Your standards definitely, definitely take
a dive when you come to a situation like
this.
When you get hungry, you'll eat anything.
At
tonight's reward challenge, we're gonna
find out just how motivated our hungry
tribes are.
During
World War II, this area was a hotspot of
military activity.
So, the premise of this challenge?
Fleeing troops have just abandoned their
barracks and left behind some very useful
items.
Two can openers, two pocket knives, and
two army helmets.
One member from each tribe will go in
together, they'll have a flashlight,
you'll look for these items.
You can only find one item per person.
You come back out, you hand off the
flashlight which sort of acts like a baton
to the next person and they go in.
Be careful, if you bring back a duplicate
item, your tribe will be disqualified.
There's a little bit about what you're
playing for tonight.
We've got some good canned food.
Peas, some tuna, a little dessert.
Is that chocolate?
That is chocolate.
First tribe back, with all the items on
the list, wins.
You guys ready?
We can stick together, really, as Pagong
still and just...
Colleen, she said that she does not want
to vote anybody in our team off until all
of their team is gone.
We want to stick together.
But Jenna also has said that she is not
going to vote anybody in our team off.
Greg said openly that he's not going to
vote anybody in the team off.
Jervis has said it openly.
I've said it numerous times openly.
I've never heard Gretchen say, I want to
keep this team together.
What do you think?
I
don't see myself joining a voting
alliance.
But if it's somebody that I'm thinking of
voting off, that would be great.
I'll vote along with everybody else.
If we win and we go in with an advantage,
we just all got to stick together, stay as
a team like we've been doing all the
while.
Joel seems to be ignoring the fact that we
combine the tribes.
And if we lose it, somebody is being voted
off.
And he talks way too much about what he's
going to do when the tribes are combined,
the strategy, the combination.
What if he doesn't make it to the
combining of the tribes?
I know that ladies' man has irritated
every woman in his tribe.
I'm not a chauvinist.
I believe that a woman can do anything a
man can do.
Joel thinks he's the All-American and all
of these physical challenges are just
feeding his ego.
Go ahead.
If you want to compete with me, I'm fine
with it.
I've lost any competitions.
You know, he's golden boy.
He's Mr. January.
He's going to have a calendar.
Think
of anything that I've done that's bad.
To, uh, be pretty condescending.
Like, he has to explain everything so
thoroughly that we just couldn't
understand it without Joel.
Throw it over there.
I know that game he tastes is going to be
pretty harsh.
I don't see why he feels the need to treat
us like we're children.
I wouldn't pry with that.
I wouldn't pry with the tip of that thing.
Do we have a butter knife over there?
He is full of, don't do this, put it here,
do that, watch out, da da da.
Well, then get up and do it.
You can't be a woman who's strong enough
to volunteer to come here and take what
comes.
Do you want me to get that for you?
And then overlook a comment like he
doesn't trust you to cook the rice.
Have we been throwing the water and the
rice in there all at one time?
Yeah.
Why?
I just want to, usually at home I boil the
water and then I throw the rice.
A woman just is not capable of doing the
things as good.
As he is.
We'll go without some rice for a little
while and it'll be okay.
And it took us a while to even bring it up
to each other.
But once we did, it's like, oh, you feel
that way too?
And I know that, you know, all three of us
are feeling that.
Alright.
I said what I said.
I'm totally square with everything across
the board, whatever anybody thinks.
But no, I definitely am not a chauvinist.
For the last immunity challenge before the
merger, an official U.S.
Army obstacle course has been constructed
by the Green Berets.
Hey Rudy, look behind you.
Pushes?
You know, make us work hard for this
victory.
Because we're, I mean, we're coming full
steam ahead at it.
Day 18 on the island.
For the past few days, the tribes have had
their minds on just one thing.
The merger.
Tomorrow, the two tribes become one.
Nobody can predict the impact of
unification.
As new alliances will form, strategies
will change.
That makes today's immunity challenge
critical.
If Tagi loses, they enter the merger
outnumbered by Pagong six to four.
Could then be eliminated by a Pagong
voting alliance.
We're thinking we can do this.
On the other hand, if Pagong loses, the
tribes will merge even at five members
each.
Joel and Jenna will run the first half of
the course for Pagong.
Sean and Kelly, for Tagi.
They will meet their two fellow tribe
members, Rich and Susan for Tagi, and
Gretchen and Greg for Pagong, at an
obstacle called Blown Bridge.
All four will negotiate this obstacle and
then race to the finish line where the
tribe members who are not participating in
the race, Rudy for Tagi, and Colleen and
Jervis for Pagong, are waiting to cheer
them on.
Yeah!
Survivors ready?
Go!
Which
requires them to now stop and think,
because this obstacle involves strategy.
We've got to get up.
Can't touch the middle.
The runners are carrying the instructions
on how to proceed.
We have to start from here.
Each tribe is given four boards of various
links.
The object, use the boards to move all
four tribe members across the pylons
without touching the sand.
After you're gonna leave the tops.
Oh, really?
We're still shifting boards around here.
Doesn't
matter if they're ahead of you, just take
your time.
Watch your hands.
Never panic.
It's already been tenderized.
The console is a necessary part of the
game, but it's the nasty part of the game.
It's the part that I enjoy the least, and
that I could do without.
I don't know who's gonna go.
It could be anybody.
Service.
You're just as chauvinistic as Joel.
This game is much too vicious for my
board.
I'm gonna be back at home and be like,
God, that's so easy.
I feel like we're gonna go to tribal
council and vote one person off.
Yeah.
I feel like this is the end of our
survivor run here, and we're all about to
go back to our lives, and I won't talk to
these guys.
Another night of reckoning at tribal
council.
So tonight's agenda is the same as always
at tribal council.
You guys will have to vote off one member.
So before we get to that, Joel, were you
surprised to lose today?
You know, I don't know if we were really
surprised.
I mean, I knew that we were physically
stronger and faster.
We pushed as hard as we could today, and
came up a little bit short this time.
It's no big secret about the comments that
were made regarding women in comparison to
an animal.
God, those cows.
What was your take on that, Gretchen?
It's being made light of here, but from
what I gathered, it wasn't necessarily
taken all that lightly.
I wasn't there for the initial
conversation.
They were storytelling at night, I think.
And I don't really believe that Jervis...
Oh, were we not supposed to say anything?
Come on!
What do you mean, come on?
You didn't say anything?
You know, Jeff, I do not even recall
saying these words.
Oh, my God.
And you know what?
You know what, Jervis?
Right now is when they are going to play
you saying words.
It sounds so much like Joel, but...
When I listen to it, it sounds so much
like Joel.
Don't let me offend you or anything.
Keep it right over there.
Well, who...
To clear it up from your guys' take on it,
Jenna, who...
Did you link Joel in that group also?
I got linked into this somehow.
I have no idea.
It was this thing.
It kind of linked in.
I don't know.
Alright.
Whatever.
Jervis, last time I asked you if you
felt...
If anybody here felt invincible.
You were the first one to pipe up.
You said, I'm not going anywhere.
Still feel that way tonight?
I refuse to answer that question.
On the ground.
That my invincibility may be affected by
that.
So that's a yes.
Alright.
Yes!
I'm feeling real good tonight.
Why?
Just because, man.
I don't know what it is.
I mean, it might just be me, but...
I'm feeling good.
Anybody here want to own up to feeling a
little...
Uncertain about their future in the next
five to ten minutes?
It's time to vote.
Joel?
I picked Joel for two reasons.
Both small ones.
He seems a bit condescending to women, and
it makes it difficult to work with.
And two, he seems to have the most money
of anybody, so...
I think he needs to win less.
I think towards us ladies.
Moo!
Just a step above a cow.
On the island, fire represents life here
at Tribal Council.
Your torches represent your life, your
identity.
Directly across from you are the five
torches from the first five people voted
off.
Tonight, one of your torches will be added
to that group.
I'll go tally the votes.
Let's read the votes.
First vote.
Jenna.
Two votes for Joel, two votes for Jenna.
Last vote.
The rest of you guys, a whole new ball
game tomorrow.
Two tribes will merge into one.
You can head back to your camp.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Good night.
Next week on Survivor.
The two tribes merge into one.
I think it'll be interesting.
I think it'll set up a whole nother set of
interpersonal dynamics.
This group is going to work out so well.
The whole ten.
This new group is like...
It's like a banquet.
Personally, it's a pain in the ass.
If you want to win this money, you gotta
get a little dirty.
I wish I could've made it a little longer.
I think maybe the girls on the team maybe
had a little inferiority complex.
That they took some of these remarks
wrong.
They think I'm a chauvinist.
I'm definitely not.
I mean, so that is my main regret.
That I'm gonna leave here and I got, you
know, four people that think I'm a
chauvinist.
I'm a chauvinist.
You know, I, I, I, I, I, I, I, I'm going
to die.